Guide to the John R. Blaney papers, 1953-2001 and undated RL.11598
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John R. Blaney papers
1953-2001 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Blaney, John R., 1931-
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11598
15.0 Linear Feet
Advertising executive who worked for the Ogilvy & Mather agency in New York and London. Collection includes correspondence, financial and research reports, client and new business presentations, speeches, policy manuals, booklets and other printed materials, as well as videocassettes and print advertisements that document Blaney's work in client services, staff training and general management at Ogilvy & Mather. Companies represented include American Express, Chesebrough-Pond's, Nestle, Procter & Gamble, Shell, SmithKline Beecham and Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Accounts; Ogilvy & Mather; Print Material; Writings and Speeches; Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Advertising executive who worked for the Ogilvy & Mather agency in New York and London. Born 1931, Brooklyn, N.Y. Fordham University, College of Pharmacy. Military service 1953-1955. New York University Business School, 1955. 1955-1961 R.H. Macy's, buyer. 1961-1964, whelan Drug Store, manager. Ogilvy & Mather: Account Supervisor (1964); Vice President (1968); Senior Vice President (1979); General Manager O&M New YOrk (1982-1986); President O&M Healthcare (1982-1986); Worldwide Management Supervisor--Unilever, Shell, SmithKline Beecham (1986-1991); Executive Director, Worldwide Clients (1991-1994). Retired 1994.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The John R. Blaney papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2018.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
David B. McCall papers
Jock Elliott papers
Joel Raphaelson papers
Kenneth Roman papers
Reva Korda papers
Robert S. Smith papers
William E. Phillips papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, financial and research reports, client and new business presentations, speeches, policy manuals, booklets and other printed materials, as well as videocassettes and print advertisements that document Blaney's work in client services, staff training and general management at Ogilvy & Mather. Companies represented include American Express, Chesebrough-Pond's, Nestle, Procter & Gamble, Shell, SmithKline Beecham and Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- Great Britain; Advertising -- United States -- Sources; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- Management; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- Great Britain; Advertising executives -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; American Express Company; Chesebrough-Pond's.; Nestlé; Ogilvy & Mather; Procter & Gamble Company; Shell Oil Company; SmithKline Beecham; Unilever (Firm)
- General Files, 1960-2001; undated; 1
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies), 1993-1995; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Advertising, 1984-1995 (Box 1)
  - Advertising Association (U.K.), 1995 (Box 1)
  - Advertising Club of New York, 1993-1995 (Box 1)
  - Advertising creative brief, 1991-2000 (Box 1)
  - Advertising industry, 1990-1995 (Box 1)
  - Advertising research, 1983-1990 (Box 1)
  - Advertising statistics, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
  - Agency business, 1985-1996 (Box 1)
  - Agency-client relationship, undated (Box 1)
  - Agency compensation, 1964-1980 (Box 1)
  - Agency compensation, 1972-1998; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Agency compensation--Marketing Management meeting, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Agency contracts, 1991-1998; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Agency evaluations, 1980-1998 (Box 2)
  - Agency financials, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Agency management, 1976-1993 (Box 2)
  - Agency management, 1990-1999 (Box 3)
  - Agency questionnaire, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Agency relations, 1978-1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Agency selection, 1984 (Box 3)
  - American Marketing Association, 1994-1996 (Box 3)
  - Anatomy of a marketing plan, undated (Box 3)
  - Biographical sketch, approximately 1994 (Box 3)
  - Branding, 1982-1991; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Branding speeches, 1985-1991 (Box 3)
  - Brands and branding, 1984-2001; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Building worldwide client business, 1983-1992; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Business-top-business advertising, 1978-1994 (Box 4)
  - Client services, 1988-1996; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Company strategy, 1982-1993 (Box 4)
  - Conferences, 1994-1996 (Box 5)
  - Conferences, 1994-1996 (Box 5)
  - Consultants, 1984-1996 (Box 5)
  - Corporate advertising, 1982-1999 (Box 5)
  - Creative, 1973-1995; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Direct marketing, 1993-1996 (Box 5)
  - Direct-to-consumer, 1993-2000; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Direct-to-consumer, 1993-2000; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Global marketing, 1978-1998; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Healthcare advertising, 1979-1996 (Box 6)
  - Interactive advertising, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - International advertising, 1974-2000; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - International advertising, 1986 (Box 31)
  - International Advertising Association, 1990-1996; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Leadership, 1972; undated (Box 7)
  - Management principles, undated (Box 7)
  - Marchese Communications, 1995-1996; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Marketing, 1960-1994 (Box 8)
  - Marketing course--Advertising, 1979; undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Marketing course--Developing new products, 1980; undated (Box 8)
  - Marketing course--Distribution, 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Marketing course--Elements of a marketing plan, 1961; undated (Box 8)
  - Marketing course--Overview, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Marketing course--Packaging, 1979-1980 (Box 8)
  - Marketing course--Product concept and positioning, 1979; undated (Box 8)
  - Marketing course--Products, 1978; undated (Box 8)
  - Marketing course--Promotion, undated, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Marketing course--Session 1, 1966-1980; undated (Box 9)
  - Marketing course--Session 2, undated, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Marketing course--Spending, undated (Box 9)
  - Media, 1969-1994 (Box 9)
  - New products, 1983-1993 (Box 9)
  - New York Public Library, 1993-1995 (Box 9)
  - Nonprescription Drug Manufacturers Association, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Nuggets (quote file), 1986-1990 (Box 9)
  - Nutriceuticals, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Pacific Rim, 1993-1995 (Box 9)
  - Pacific Rim, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Packaging, 1989-1991 (Box 10)
  - Planning, 1995; undated (Box 10)
  - Private brands, 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Pro bono, 1993-1995 (Box 10)
  - Research, 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Reviving old brands, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Role of advertising, 1986-1995 (Box 10)
  - Sales promotion, 1990-1992 (Box 10)
  - Teaching files, 1986-1996; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Trends file, 1987-1994 (Box 10)
- Accounts, 1967-2001; undated; 2
  - American Express, 1985-1992; undated; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - American Express--Coordination case study, undated (Box 11)
  - American Express--Traveler's Cheques, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Bahamas Ministry of Tourism, 1987 (Box 11)
  - Bristol Myers Squibb, 1993-1994 (Box 11)
  - Burberry, 1995 (Box 11)
  - Chesebrough Pond's, 1990-1995; 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Chesebrough Pond's--Brandprint, undated (Box 11)
  - Chesebrough Pond's--Branding, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Chesebrough Pond's--Debriefing, 1992 (Box 11)
  - Chesebrough Pond's--Poind's Institute, 1992-1993 (Box 11)
  - DuPont, 2000-2001 (Box 11)
  - DuPont--Corian print advertisements, undated (Box 31)
  - Duracell--Building a Worldwide Brand, 1995 (Box 11)
  - Duracell pitch, 1995 (Box 11)
  - Elida Pond's--Cutex, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Ferrero Rocher, 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - General Foods--Marketing principles, 1976-1978 (Box 12)
  - General Foods--Maxwell House brand essence, 1993 (Box 12)
  - General Foods--Why Your Advertising Agency Needs a Better Product, 1995 (Box 12)
  - Glaxo, 1992; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Goldman Sachs, 1994 (Box 12)
  - Goldman Sachs--Competitive financial services print advertisements, 1994 (Box 31)
  - International Paper Company print advertisements, 1979 (Box 31)
  - Jaguar, 1995; undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Kraft General Foods--Trade Support Television Advertising, 1993 (Box 12)
  - Lufthansa, 1994 (Box 12)
  - Merck, 1992 (Box 12)
  - Miles Laboratories--Alka-Seltzer Plus brand audit, 1993 (Box 12)
  - Nestle, 1991-1993; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Nestle--Branding policy, undated (Box 12)
  - Nestle--The Brand Is the Business, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Nike, 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - Novartis (Box 13)
  - Pepsi (Mirinda, 7-Up) (Box 13)
  - Philips--Why Philips Needs Aligned Advertising Agencies and Co-Ordinated Campaigns (Box 13)
  - Procter & Gamble, 1977-1995; 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Procter & Gamble--Acquisition of Richardson Vicks and Noxell, undated (Box 13)
  - Procter & Gamble--Re-Engineering the Global Dragon, 1994 (Box 13)
  - Procter & Gamble--Roar of the Global Dragon, 1992 (Box 13)
  - Richardson Vicks, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Roche, 1998-1999 (Box 14)
  - Roche--Rocephin tactical plan, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Shell, 1990-1994; undated; 7 folders (Box 14)
  - Shell--Brand personality, undated (Box 14)
  - Shell--Brand positioning/personality, undated (Box 14)
  - Shell--Brand stewardship presentation, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Shell--How to Make Effective Use of Corporate Advertising, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Shell--Managing the Shell Brand, undated (Box 15)
  - SmithKline Beecham, 1992-1995; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - SmithKline Beecham--Case studies, 1990-1994 (Box 15)
  - SmithKline Beecham--Category management communication programme, undated (Box 15)
  - SmithKline Beecham--Overview of O&M Work, undated (Box 15)
  - SmithKline Beecham--Print advertisements, undated (Box 31)
  - SmithKline Beecham--Tagamet-100 direct marketing, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Thomas J. Lipton--Brandprint, undated (Box 15)
  - Thomas J. Lipton--Project Jupiter (homeopathy), 1993 (Box 15)
  - Unilever, 1985-1998; 5 folders (Box 15)
  - Unilever, 1992-1993 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Acorns into Oaks: How to Grow with Unilever, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Advertising Evaluation: Recommended Methodology for Europe, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Agency alignment policy, 1985-1991 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Agency compensation, 1971-1991 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Brand stewardship, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Brochure, undated (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Business of Care, undated (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Concept vs. positioning, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Creative review, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Detergents, 1967-1993; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Direct marketing, 1986-1992; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Dove brandprint, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Dove case studies, 1991-1993 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Effective Use of Theme Marketing, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--"Feedback" direct marketing, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Helene Curtis: Degree deodorant, undated (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Life and Lore of Dove, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Management and organisation, 1983 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Market Leaders Around the World, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--Max Blackston talk to Detergents Group, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Unilever--New Product Development Guide, 1969 (Box 17)
  - Unilever--Plan for Great Advertising, 1988 (Box 17)
  - Unilever--Presentations, 1987-1990 (Box 17)
  - Unilever--Presentations on Kao, 1989-1990 (Box 17)
  - Unilever--Role of Marketing Division, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Unilever--Story of Sunlight (soap), 1984 (Box 17)
  - Unilever Foods/Lipton, 1989-1995; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Visiting Nurse Service of New York, 1999; undated; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Visiting Nurse Service of New York--Print advertisements, undated (Box 31)
  - WorldSource, undated (Box 17)
- Ogilvy & Mather (O&M), 1955-1999; undated; 3
  - General, 1981-1993; undated; 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Advertising, Sales Promotion and the Bottom Line, 1989 (Box 18)
  - After the Recession (U.S. and international versions), 1992 (Box 18)
  - Alternative Paths to Persuasion, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Alumni Flagbearer, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Annual Report, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Asia-Pacific, 1993 (Box 18)
  - Asia Viewpoint, 1993 (Box 31)
  - Attitude Accessibility: On the Trail of a New Tool for Predicting Brand Choice, 1986 (Box 18)
  - Attitude Change: Making It Stick, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Brand blueprint, undated (Box 18)
  - Brand Personality, 1993 (Box 18)
  - Brand Revitalization, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Brand stewardship, 1993-1995; undated; 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Brand stewardship, 1994 (Box 31)
  - Branding and Advertising Strategy, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Branding Guidelines, 1993 (Box 18)
  - Brochure, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Brochure, 1994 (Box 31)
  - Charlotte Beers--Brand Stewardship, 1993 (Box 19)
  - Charlotte Beers--Geometry of Management, 1987 (Box 19)
  - Charlotte Beers--How a Product Becomes a Brand, 1984 (Box 19)
  - Client conflicts, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Clients, Brands, and Ogilvy & Mather, undated (Box 19)
  - Commission contract (sample), undated (Box 19)
  - Communication 2000, undated (Box 19)
  - Comparative Advertising Revisited, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Confessions--If Your Brand Becomes Expendable, Will You?, 1987 (Box 19)
  - Conflict Resolution as a Process for Overcoming Resistance to Ideas, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Consumer Trendsights, undated (Box 19)
  - Corporate Culture, undated (Box 19)
  - Corporate identity manual, undated (Box 19)
  - Creative Philosophy, 1990 (Box 19)
  - David Ogilvy, 1994-1999 (Box 19)
  - David Ogilvy--Adweek profile, 1992 (Box 19)
  - David Ogilvy--David Ogilvy Speaks Out, 1989 (Box 19)
  - David Ogilvy--Leadership: The Forgotten Factor in Management, 1972 (Box 19)
  - David Ogilvy--Obituaries and tributes, 1999 (Box 31)
  - David Ogilvy--Principles of Management, 1968 (Box 19)
  - David Ogilvy--Sound an Alarm!, 1986 (Box 19)
  - David Ogilvy--The Image and the Brand, 1955 (Box 19)
  - David Ogilvy--We Sell-Or Else, 1991-1992 (Box 19)
  - David Ogilvy, Joel Raphaelson--Research on Advertising Techniques that Work, and Don't Work (Box 19)
  - Diane Courtney--Bifocals: Why You Can't Build a Brand Without Them, undated (Box 19)
  - Diane Courtney--How Brands Succeed, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Dictionary of Advertising and Graphic Arts Terms, undated (Box 19)
  - European Training Group Participants, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Finding the Arthritis Sufferer, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Flagbearer, 1995 (Box 31)
  - Food advertising, 1984-1992 (Box 19)
  - Future of Pharmaceuticals, 1989 (Box 20)
  - Getting to the Idea, undated (Box 20)
  - Global client services, 1992; undated (Box 20)
  - Graham Phillips--Conference Board speech, 1986 (Box 20)
  - Graham Phillips--Creative Standards, 1991 (Box 20)
  - Graham Phillips--How to Build Brand Identity in Times of Chaos, 1988 (Box 20)
  - Graham Phillips--Time for Change, 1992 (Box 20)
  - Healthcare advertising, 1972-1992; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Hot Topics, undated (Box 20)
  - How Advertising Works, 1986 (Box 20)
  - How OBM Believes Television Advertising Works, 1973 (Box 20)
  - How to Create Winning Advertising Strategies, 1984 (Box 20)
  - How to Do Ads, undated (Box 20)
  - How to Launch New Products Successfully, 1986 (Box 20)
  - How to Present and Sell Advertising, 1979 (Box 20)
  - How to Win New Business, 1984 (Box 20)
  - How We Plan and Develop Advertising, undated (Box 20)
  - Impact of Advertising Expenditures on Profits for Consumer Businesses, 1987 (Box 20)
  - Input, 1989 (Box 21)
  - Integrated Services, 1984 (Box 21)
  - International advertising, undated (Box 21)
  - ISP Awards, 1989 (Box 21)
  - Jane Fitzgibbon--View 2000, 1989 (Box 21)
  - Jennifer Stewart--Speech to World Wildlife Federation, 1984 (Box 21)
  - Jock Elliott--Hall of Fame speech, 1984 (Box 21)
  - Kenneth Roman--Creative Management, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Kenneth Roman--Who We Are, And Where We're Not Going, 1988 (Box 21)
  - Kenneth Roman--Why Brands Fail, 1983 (Box 21)
  - Kenneth Roman, Joel Raphaelson--How to Write Better, 1978 (Box 21)
  - Lantern--How to Create Advertising That Crosses Borders, 1990 (Box 21)
  - Let's Talk Training, 1990-1994 (Box 21)
  - Magic Lantern--Creating Advertisements for Newspapers and Magazines, 1987 (Box 21)
  - Magic Lantern--How to Market in Developing Countries, 1987 (Box 21)
  - Managing Worldwide Client Services, 1989; undated (Box 21)
  - Marketing to Europe, 1992 (Box 21)
  - Meetings (photographs and memorabilia, Budapest and Latin America), undated (Box 22)
  - Michel Richardot, Curtis Lesage (Paris)--New business presentation, 1980 (Box 22)
  - Mission statement card, undated (Box 22)
  - Mission statements, 1993; undated; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - New business, 1984-1986 (Box 22)
  - New Business Plan, 1992 (Box 22)
  - New business prospects list, 1987 (Box 22)
  - New Employee Book, undated, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - New products, 1965-1989 (Box 22)
  - New Products Magic Lantern, 1990 (Box 22)
  - Norman Berry--Revitalizing Brands, 1987 (Box 22)
  - Norman Berry--Speech on corporate image, 1981 (Box 22)
  - Norman Berry--Value of Branding, 1987 (Box 22)
  - Norman Berry, Richard Fowler--Big Idea, 1988 (Box 22)
  - Ogilvy & Mather Healthcare, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Ogilvy & Mather's View of Worldwide Advertising, undated (Box 22)
  - Ogilvy Orchestration booklets, 1985-1988 (Box 23)
  - Over 50s: How to Reach Out to an Ignored Consumer, 1988 (Box 23)
  - Packaging Research, 1989 (Box 23)
  - Personnel policies, 1987-1996 (Box 23)
  - Premium brands, 1986-1987 (Box 23)
  - Prescription Drug Advertising, 1992 (Box 23)
  - Print Lantern, 1986 (Box 23)
  - Profits & Prophecy, 1985 (Box 23)
  - Proposal to Promote Russia as a Business Venue, 1993 (Box 23)
  - Public Relations, 1990 (Box 23)
  - Report Writing, undated (Box 23)
  - Reva Korda--The Loneliness of the Long Distance Watcher, 1977 (Box 23)
  - Richard Fowler--Effective TV Advertising, 1987 (Box 23)
  - Richard Fowler--Ice cream presentation: Euro Glace, 1986 (Box 23)
  - Richard Fowler--The Core Idea, 1992 (Box 23)
  - RMS (Regional Management Supervisor), 1992 (Box 23)
  - Roadmap to the New Ogilvy & Mather, undated (Box 23)
  - Rod Wright--The Forces Shaping Marketing and Advertising in Asia, 1992 (Box 31)
  - Sales Promotion, undated (Box 23)
  - Skin Care Evolution and Trends, 1992 (Box 23)
  - Slice of Life Magic Lantern, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Speeches by various staff, 1977-1991; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Strategic plans, 1987-1993 (Box 24)
  - Strategy, undated (Box 24)
  - The Ogilvy & Mather Business Book, 1988 (Box 24)
  - The Ogilvy & Mather Training Book, 1987 (Box 24)
  - The Ogilvy Client Commitment, undated (Box 24)
  - The People Book, 1987 (Box 24)
  - The Welcome Book, undated (Box 24)
  - There's No Business Like New Business, 1984 (Box 24)
  - Training, 1984-1994 (Box 25)
  - Training: It Is Our History, It Is Our Future, 1982 (Box 25)
  - Trend Watch, 1993 (Box 25)
  - View 2000, undated (Box 31)
  - Viewpoint, 1977-1994; 6 folders (Box 25)
  - Viewpoint, 1994 (Box 26)
  - We Sell, Or Else, 1982 (Box 26)
  - What Makes a Commercial Likeable?, 1986 (Box 26)
  - What Ogilvy & Mather Believes About Creating Advertising, 1979 (Box 26)
  - What Ogilvy & Mather Has Learned About How Much to Spend on Advertising, undated (Box 26)
  - What Ogilvy & Mather Has Learned So Far About Business-to-Business Advertising, 1993 (Box 26)
  - What Ogilvy & Mather Has Learned So Far About Financial Advertising, 1984 (Box 26)
  - What Ogilvy & Mather Knows About Advertising Analgesics, 1994 (Box 26)
  - What OBM Knows About Added Value, 1975 (Box 26)
  - What's the Return on Quality?, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Why You Should Hire Us, undated (Box 26)
  - William Phillips--Speaking the Same Language Does Not Always Mean Thinking the Same: The Anglo-American Paradox, 1985 (Box 26)
  - William Phillips--Speech file, 1986-1989 (Box 26)
  - William Weed--How to Create a Creative Climate, undated (Box 26)
  - Worldwide client service, 1993 (Box 26)
- Print Material, 1953-2000; undated; 4
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)--Advertising: A Guide to Careers in Advertising, 1975 (Box 26)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)--Client's Guide to Ad Agency Service: In-House or Independent?, 1993 (Box 26)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)--Client's Guide to Agency-Client Contracts, 1993 (Box 26)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)--Client's Guide to Agency Compensation, 1994 (Box 26)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)--Client's Guide to the AAAA Agency, 1993 (Box 26)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)--Client's Guide to Working with Your AAAA Agency, 1993 (Box 26)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)--Integrated Communications, 1991 (Box 26)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)--What Every Account Executive Should Know About a Marketing Plan, 1990 (Box 26)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)--What Every Account Executive Should Know About Agency Management, 1987 (Box 26)
  - Advertising Age--Procter & Gamble 150th Anniversary Issue, 1987 (Box 31)
  - Advertising Age--Tribute to Leo Burnett 60th Anniversary, 1995 (Box 31)
  - Advertising Association (U.K.)--Executive Briefs on Key Issues in Advertising, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Advertising Association (U.K.)--Promoting and Protecting the Freedom to Advertise, 1994 (Box 26)
  - Alexander Biel--Love the Ad. Buy the Product?, undated (Box 26)
  - Alvin Achenbaum--Transformation of Packaged Food Marketing, 1989 (Box 26)
  - AMA (American Marketing Association)--Baby Boomers Turn 50, 1996 (Box 26)
  - AMA (American Marketing Association)--Customer Satisfaction, 1992 (Box 27)
  - ANA (Association of National Advertisers)--Advertising Services, 1991 (Box 27)
  - ANA (Association of National Advertisers)--Agency Compensation Guidebook, 1989 (Box 27)
  - ANA (Association of National Advertisers)--Fee Methods of Agency Compensation, 1969 (Box 27)
  - ANA (Association of National Advertisers)--Selecting an Advertising Agency, undated (Box 27)
  - Anthony Weir--How to Brief Your Advertising Agency, 1983 (Box 27)
  - Apple computer booklet, 1984 (Box 27)
  - CAM Galaxy--Business Plan, undated (Box 27)
  - Center for Research and Development--Options and Opportunities for Consumer Businesses: Advertising During a Recession, 1990 (Box 27)
  - Charles Mittelstadt--Brand Power, 1989 (Box 27)
  - Conference Board--Organizing for Global Competitiveness, 1993 (Box 27)
  - Creativity, 1995 (Box 31)
  - David Arnold--The Brand Is the Business, 1991 (Box 27)
  - David Maister--Professional Service Firm Management, 1989 (Box 27)
  - Family Circle--Family Index, 1994 (Box 27)
  - Futures Group--Background information and qualification, undated (Box 27)
  - Interbrand--Class of '88 (new brands), 1989 (Box 28)
  - International Advertising Association, 1994-1998 (Box 28)
  - International Advertising Association--Medicine Advertising Regulation, 1985 (Box 28)
  - International Advertising Association--The Case for Advertising, 1994-1995 (Box 28)
  - J. Walter Thompson--T-Plan, 1977 (Box 28)
  - John Mickletwait--The Party's Over, 1990 (Box 28)
  - Larry Light--Building Brand Relationships, 1993 (Box 28)
  - Larry Light--The Fourth Wave: Brand Loyalty Marketing, 1994 (Box 28)
  - Managing Brand Equity, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Marketing education articles, 1993 (Box 28)
  - Martin Puris--Beyond the Brand Experience, 1996 (Box 31)
  - McCann Erickson--Creative Works, undated (Box 28)
  - New York Herald front page collection (1929) for International Advertising Convention, undated (Box 31)
  - Paine Webber newsletters, 1992-1993 (Box 28)
  - Paul Ray, Carre Orran--Recruitment brochures, undated (Box 28)